Profile

A highly motivated student who is using his programming skills to deal with data, mostly seismological. Seeking for an position in either data science industry to be able face new challenges all the time. Multiple projects conducted in students' societies provided a lot of experience both as a team player and a team leader. With five years of experience in solving scientific problems with programming and half of a year on a junior backend developer position he proved to be able to quickly adapt and learn new techniques and technologies. Now, ready to face completely new challenges in either industry. Currently working on a PhD thesis which includes many data engineering tasks such as data aggregation, processing and visualization in a production grade technological stack including technologies such as Docker-Compose, PostgreSQL, Apache Airflow.

Education

Oct 2017 – Present **Doctor of Science in Seismology**, *Institut de Physique du Globe de Strasbourg*,

Thesis title: Monitoring of deep reservoirs with ambient seismic noise,

Supervisors: Jerome Vergne, PhD. IPGS, Jean Schmittbuhl.

Keywords: Ambient Seismic Noise Interferometry, Python, Data Science, ETL, Apache Airflow,

PostgreSQL.

Oct 2015 – Jul 2017 Master of Science in Geophysics, University of Silesia in Katowice,

Thesis title: Seismic noise analysis for purpose of Active Layer of Permafrost investiga-

tions in a region of Polish Polar Station in Hornsund, Svalbard, Supervisor: Dorota Olszewska, PhD. Institute of Geophysics, PAS.

Keywords: HVSR, Local effects, Python, ObsPy, Matlab, Git.

Oct 2012 - Jun 2015 Bachelor of Science in Geophysics, University os Silesia in Katowice,

Thesis title: Seismic network optimization in the LGCD area with use of simulated

annealing algorithm,

Supervisor: Maciej Mendecki, PhD. University of Silesia. Keywords: Matlab, Monte Carlo Sampling, D-optimum solution.

Experience

April 2017 - Sep 2017 Junior Java Developer, ACC Cyfronet AGH.

Responsibilities Programming in Java with use of Spring, MongoDB, GWT, Angular. Programming in

Python with use of ObsPy, Numpy, Scipy.

May 2016 – Nov 2016 Intern, Institute of Geophysics, Polish Academy of Sciences.

Internship coordinator Dorota Olszewska, PhD.

Responsibilities Creating Python scripts to process seismic signal to apply HVSR method; Creating and

maintaining SQLite database of PGA parameters for LGCD region; Creating Python

scripts for solving different problems and tasks in the Institute

Jun 2015 – Jul 2015 Intern, , Institute of Geophysics, Polish Academy of Sciences.

Internship coordinator Dorota Olszewska, PhD.

Responsibilities Seismic signal processing in Matlab; HVSR method inplementation in Matlab

Jan 2015 - Oct 2017 Member of a scientific project, University of Silesia in Katowice.

Member of a project *Permafrost interaction as an environmental continuum between glacial and periglacial domain in Tarfala (Scandinavia) and Hornsund area, Spitsbergen* under leadership

Page 1 of 2

of dr hab. Wojciech Dobiński, University of Silesia, Department of Earth Science. Participant of the Scientific Expedition to the Spitsbergen in Aug - Sep 2015

Responsibilities Preparing and conducting Electrical Resistivity Tomography surveys; Data processing

and interpretation

67000 Strasbourg - France

Programming

Python 4 years of experience Obspy, Scipy, Numpy, Matplotlib, Pandas, SQLalchemy

Java 1 year of experience Spring, Springboot, GWT

SQL 2 years of experience

Utilities Docker, Docker Compose, Apache Airflow, Git, Latex, Bash, TravisCI, CircleCI

Databases SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Minor experience R, Matlab

Voluntary Services

Oct 2015 – Aug 2016 **Organizing Committee Member**.

7th International Geosciences Student Conference in Katowice, 11th -14th July 2016

Responsibilities Organization of worldwide sceintific conference for 150 students and young professionals

as a core member of organizing committee

Jan 2016 Volunteer, Biebrza National Park, Poland..

Responsibilities Data preparation, processing and preparing for publishing in form of maps using ArcGis

software.

Oct 2014 – May 2015 **Organizing Committee Leader**.

VIII Student Scientific Workshops Geosfera 2015 in Żory, 23-26th April 2015

Responsibilities Organization of scientific conference for 130 students as leader of organizing committee

Languages

Polish Native

English B2/C1 Full professional fluency

French Elementary Russian Elementary

Grants and Awards

2016 — Best Student Poster Award of Session 18 during 35th General Meeting of European Seimological Commision, Trieste 2016

 Travel grant to participate in Advanced School on Seismology Beyond Textbooks & 35th General Meeting of European Seimological Commission, Trieste, 2016

2015 — Travel Grant to participate in Society of Exploration Geophysicists & Chevron Student Leadership Symposium, New Orleans, 2015.

2012 — Winner of the XVI Contest of Technical Knowledge 2012, organized by University of Silesia in Katowice (XVI Konkurs Wiedzy Technicznej).

Student Scientific Associations

Oct 2012 – Jul 2017 Student Science Association of Geophysicists PREM Positions: Vicepresident, Member

Jan 2014 – Jul 2017 University of Silesia Student Chapter of the EAGE Positions: President

Jan 2015 – Jul 2017 University of Silesia Student Chapter of the SEG Positions: President, Vicepresident

Personal interests

- o Hiking, running, swimming, mountaineering, polar regions
- o Technology, IT, programming
- o Seismology, geophysics, statistics, data science

Page 2 of 2